# PRESTON SHAW

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Ambitious Junior Web Developer brings enthusiasm and detailed understanding of various programming languages to webpage planning, development and maintenance. Experience designing and developing sites from concept to roll out. Foundational grasp of various CSS and HTML options, development platforms and security requirements.

#### **SKILLS**

- Front-End Programming: HTML5, CSS3, AJAX
- Scripting Languages: PHP, Python, JavaScript
- Web and Application Servers
- Software Deployment
- NET Framework
- Express Js & NodeJS
- POC and Prototyping
- JavaScript Libraries and Frameworks
- JS Frameworks: React, Angular, Vue
- · Databases: Oracle, MongoDB

#### WORK HISTORY

## JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER 09/2019 to Current

Palm & Sol, Los Angeles, United States

- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.
- Developed wireframes, site maps and content inventories for new website designs.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress, Hubspot and other editing software.
- Collaborated with marketing, representing web team to establish project goals, projections and milestones while handling up to 12 client requests a day.

## **APPLICATION FOR PHOTO FACIAL RECOGNITION** 01/2022 to 10/2022

Los Angeles, United States

- Provided security maintenance and patching on interface in development of software.
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve user problems.
- Worked in a group of peers, decisively divvying roles and components to the app to assure speedy development and clear areas of control.

## APPLICATION FOR CAMPING SITE REVIEW W/ MEDIA POSTING 02/2021 to 08/2021

Los Angeles, United States

- Planned, Developed, and Executed applicated with multi-user interface and review functions.
- Reviewed database performance and function, and devised solutions to simplify future developments and errors.
- Ran analysis to understand potential leaks and losses, then provided fail-safes and error handling software.

#### **EDUCATION**